The more personal something gets, the
less likely you're going to get trust
out of a person to want to go to a
machine. Patients don't go to the
hospital just for fun. I never want to
stomp on anybody who actually suffers
from conditions like this unless you
have a medical condition where it's like
uh patients are going to providers
because there's something that they need
to have addressed. There's something
with their health that's at stake and
it's survival. This isn't something that
you want to put in front of a machine.
So trust building in a personal
experience, you really need a human in
the middle in order to be able to build
that trust. A machine is never going to
be able to quote unquote understand what
it is I might be going through. It can
mimic language to suggest that, but a
human on the other side is going to snap
and react very quickly to that. Today in
The Signal Room, I'm joined by Brian
Sutherland, elite AI product manager and
adviser focused on a customerf facing AI
and high consequence healthcare
environments. Brian built Humana's first
member-facing intelligent virtual
assistant, a platform now generating
more than $7 million in annual savings
while improving patient experience,
including a 31% lift in task completion
and measurable gains and satisfaction.
That combination financial impact and
human impact is rare. His perspective on
AI is not abstract. It's shaped by
decades of watching his mother navigate
a health system fragmented across
payers, providers, and pharmacies where
automation often added friction instead
of removing it. That lived experience
shows up in how he designs systems,
understands the manual processes before
automating them, pressure tests
decisions before scale makes them
irreversible, and he builds AI that
meets patients where they are, not where
the dashboard says they are. Brian
advises leaders who are building out or
buying AI and need clarity on what will
break first or trust roads and how to
make high stakes decisions they can
defend later. Brian, welcome to the
signal room. Been very excited and
looking forward to to having you on and
I just want to jump right in because
there's so many cool things that that
we're going to talk about today. Um, you
know, in our first conversation, it was
clear to me that, uh, you're you're the
right guy to come talk about some some
areas that I think are needing a lot
more attention than they're getting
these days. Let's start with one that's
probably kind of a top of- mind thing
for folks, and I seem to be seeing a lot
about this, but
where do you see AI initiatives most
commonly failing? And is it like
leadership alignment, workflow design,
operating model, or is it a combination
of those things? Oh, it's definitely a
combination. It's I don't even think I
could just say like point to one thing.
A lot of that I see really happening is
leadership will come in. They'll have a
really great and strong idea about you
know what it is that they want to do,
>> right?
>> And it's it's the you know almost the
the classic story. We have an
initiative, it becomes a whisper down
the alley game, long winded translation.
But then I also believe that we are also
up against a relatively young technology
still. There's so much that we still
don't really know as far as what
disciplines we should be really putting
forward into this, how we should be
positioning this. And so then yeah,
workflow is yet another portion of this.
So it it really does come down to all
three of these things.
you you point to something that I think
it it needs to be repeated.
>> Yeah.
>> This is still relatively um we've gotten
so used to things moving at the clip
that they're going 6 months into
something that's still relatively new.
We feel like it's legacy to us and we
forget that we're we still have a lot a
lot more u growing and learning to do to
really get these things to operate and
do the things that they're capable of.
It's so true. And and it, you know, like
the technology may be moving really
quickly as human beings, right? We're
it's in our nature. It's it's just, you
know, it's just part of us. We're wired
for comfort. We're wired to not want to
go through difficult growth, difficult
challenges. So, the technology is is
moving faster than people are willing to
change. I mean, it's a significant
friction point and it's something that
whether we like it or not. It's like
like uh what how does the old saying go?
It's uh when you know you're looking at
a a sequence of events, you're looking
at like you know a daisy chain of
processes, you're only as fast as the
slowest item in your your chain.
>> No, that that's true. It's really kind
of an interesting dilemma. We've got
these two things that are almost
opposite each other right now. the the
trust factor in human relationships has
eroded significantly, but we're still
way too quick to trust technology and I
we need to find some places in the
middle there, I think.
>> Yeah. Yeah. For real. And and I think,
you know, even talking about trust in
general, there's also because we have
plenty of sci-fi out there uh around AI
in general that has really kind of
informed us of this could turn into
something really terrible, really
catastrophic. Not to go into like doom
and gloom, but everybody's first
instinct. I'm hearing my father going,
you know, this is Skynet that's coming
around. And that in and of itself has
has sparked a lot of distrust right out
the gates.
>> And that's not even the real distrust
that we should be having in in all
truth. There's so many other layers of
distrust that we have to actually cut
through.
>> No, that's an excellent point. you know,
when you're talking about adoption and,
you know, whether we do it quickly or
not, the interesting dilemma that that I
see out there is that this pilot's
everywhere and you know, they everyone
gets excited about it, but then
>> when it gets deployed and we start to
get into it a little bit, it seems to
stop really being proliferated and and
get the traction that it should.
>> So, why is that from your perspective?
Why do they start to hit some barriers
when they get to an enterprise?
>> I mean, it it's all over the place. It's
it's pervasive, right? The this endless
supply of pilots, the the common pattern
that I I really start to see does come
back around to starting with that trust
factor. Usually,
my the big thing I I tend to spot out
almost immediately is the ambition is
larger than what was actually designed
in the system. It's not designed to
build trust. It's technically designed
to give maybe a quick answer. And we it
maybe covers we'll say like 20% of of
the big use cases that are out there.
But in in trust building, you can't just
say 20% and you're done with it, right?
The old 8020 rule. You do have to still
care for that other 80 in some fashion.
That doesn't mean we have to build
everything out, but it does mean that we
have to be considering
what do we do for that other 80. So
that's a really interesting challenge to
to try to overcome. I think expectations
are something that we don't do well with
sometimes in terms of setting them at
the right levels. And I, you know, I've
been talking to some folks recently just
about the the criticality of some of the
roles that are are not necessarily put
close to this front and center of the
process that need to be. And those are
the ones that are really going to be
helping to drive the execution and help
to really make things stick. Make sure
people are understanding what the value
really is and why it's important that
that that we're we're trying to tackle
these things. This is not a shortage of
administrative functions that really
could be done much more efficiently. We
just need to listen to the folks who
know exactly where some of the pain
points are so that we can address the
right things.
>> Yeah. And and you know, one of the ways
um like I I actually wrote about this
recently on LinkedIn. One of the the
ways that we can actually go about that
to really get as close as possible um is
to become one of the operators
ourselves. I actually had helped Tumana
with building out um one of their first
AI customerf facing AIs that that they
had out there. it was in their chat
platform and uh one of the things that
um that I recall from it was I I
actually took calls for two weeks prior
to even working on the project and the
exposure that you get from that like
hearing what the customers are actually
going through in in the case of humano
will say members because it's member
experience patient experience it
actually created a couple of different
dimensions of thought right I didn't
just see where the pain was. I also saw
where it maybe was more appropriate to
put that technology and where it was
less appropriate to put it.
>> Yeah, that's interesting is I think I'm
thinking back to, you know, when I was
working in New York, um on one occasion
I got to go have a a tour of one of the
office suites where they were you taking
care of cancer patients,
>> right?
>> And what was really remarkable to me is
that things had changed dramatically
over over the course of number of years.
And not only did it help me to
understand where some of the pain points
were, it gave me a much better
appreciation for what people are doing
day in and day out that are really right
on tip of the spear when it comes to
taking care of people. We we're just at
a very different place. So, as
frustrating as it can be for people like
us sometimes doing implementation
because we're not getting where we want
to go fast enough,
>> sometimes we need to pause and take a
look back and just see how far we've
come. And it's it really makes it
worthwhile when you when you take the
time to do that. And it you undoubtedly
will come across things you had no idea
how big the impact was. It makes the
work feel much more rewarding.
>> For sure. And and you know, even funnier
too, and I haven't done this in a while,
but returning back to that workflow,
right? Like you just said, how far we've
come. uh we we forget as as implementers
that we moved the needle and our
understandings are all built and
predicated off of an outdated workflow,
>> you know, and and we're seeing coming
back to like the original question,
we're seeing a lot of that that we have
new workflows that we really need to be
assessing and evaluating and then
figuring out where it's best to place
the technology, where are the friction
points within that existing workflow,
not the workflows of of yester year.
>> We're talking about the expectation
component for for a second here. What do
you think gets most underestimated
between the time of the executive
approval and the frontline deployment?
Because there's usually some level of
expectation that we've missed somehow.
>> Oh yeah. And you know that the uh that
that timeline is going to vary. I I in
my opinion it's going to vary from
organization to organization. Right.
your your your smaller shops like yeah I
will say like startups it's probably
pretty quick right the it's such a small
company the nervous system isn't really
>> completely blown out yet contrast that
to a fortune 500 or higher right um it
all of the the things that I I'll say we
take for granted in maybe like your
standard roll out right so you usually
have a a PMO of some sort or maybe a
change management office there's a a
running tally of these are the the key
essential items of anything that has to
be gone through that has to be done
prior to saying we feel confident and
comfortable with a production release
right
>> now it seems like that's all been
forgotten that the technology because it
introduces this new degree of speed um
the thought appears to be that really
the wrinkle was all around how do we get
the technology built faster?
>> That was never really the the issue. The
the issue is actually centered more on
how do we coordinate all of these
different competing audiences together
>> and how do we get them on the same page?
What do we need to do to instill
confidence in all of these individuals
that we're working with so that we're we
can approach a production environment
free and clear?
>> Yeah, I think some of that kind of leans
into, you know, governance conversations
to to some extent. Um, not from the way
that people traditionally think about
it. what I I hate to even say
traditionally because it's it's been
such a an academic exercise for for the
most part over the last decade or so
that I've been more heavily involved in
um you know the technology development
or even data and analytics.
How do you see
from a functional standpoint where
governance really can help in and be an
enabler versus that
the external factor that feels like
somebody's you know trying to keep us
away from things or trying to limit what
we can do
>> and and unfortunately
I I know how like how you feel about you
don't want to even say the word
traditionally right governance in and of
itself now has this perception that's
attached to it uh that governance
slows us down.
>> Exactly.
>> From the speed that we're trying to
gain. What is unfortunate is governance
really protects.
It it has the interests of what you're
doing in mind in the sense of enabling
for going forward.
>> Governance has to have a very very
significant play at least at some point
in the process. trying to help navigate
um a a partner right now through
trying to get in something into
production at this um current stage and
I won't name names for the time being
>> but the the short story is u
>> that's not me by the way everyone
>> uh but the short story for for that
particular group that there's a lot of
pioneering that's going on
and um in that pioneering
We have to at some point pull governance
in. We have to make sure that when we
pull them in that we are not just
allowing governance to turn it into a
death by committee. Um we want
governance to inform.
>> We want governance to feel confident
that you know we have been thinking
about these different areas that we have
to be really mindful of and we have to
be careful of.
>> Yes.
um but that we can't do it without them
too. That their input is important. It's
valuable
>> and that it helps to then shape and
crystallize what are the controls
necessary to be able to freely scale.
>> You're you're talking about something I
think is like really needs to be
understood much much better. When you're
thinking about it as as enable as an
enabling function,
you need to think about the the
different perspectives you want to make
sure you have in the room to make sure
that you're asking the right questions,
make sure that you're solving the right
problems. Um, often times there's a the
initial what I would call the survey or
if you want to want to call it some I
don't even know what to call it, but you
know, you have a listening session, you
take have identify a few different
takeaways, right? Then people go and
will build something in a vacuum and
come back and there's a surprise waiting
for them that it actually is not meeting
the need that they thought they were
trying to address.
>> Yeah.
>> That that it's really an involvement in
a relationship that has to actually be
engaged. And when you're dealing with
AI, there's an evolution. Your models
are always going to be training. So
there's got to be a really functional
cycle that a company in well development
and deployment an ongoing operation of
the of the solutions we put in place
because it's going to continue to learn
at least theoretically and it's going to
solve a whole set of problems and then
at some point in time we should see
enough of a transformation that we can
actually start addressing some deeper
things or go further. But we've got to
have that the rigor and the the
procedural um aspects of making sure
that we are governing and we are
monitoring and we are constantly having
the different perspectives looking at
the things that we're working on.
>> Yeah. I mean it's the yes and at this
point um because it's everything that
you just highlighted Chris and with
those additional perspectives um the the
failure of of what happens when you have
somebody take these specs go off into a
silo start building the blind spots that
no one can really predict or anticipate.
You're never going to see those blind
spots on your own. Uh and then this
introduces yet another perspective that
wasn't even considered. When blind spots
start to get surfaced and we start to
pressure test against those blind spots,
there is a natural order of resistance.
And from what I at least my personal
experience, usually that resistance is
based on I didn't really think about
that when we first started. We've moved
down the journey so far already. And
I've made some pretty big commitments
right now. So now what do I do? Do I go
back and now have to renegotiate on
those commitments?
>> And what kind of fallout am I going to
feel from that? Um, so that's a little
bit of of my own um recognition of what
an appreciation of what certain
individuals who are getting that
pressure,
what they're feeling and how do you
really navigate through that challenge,
right? What what expectations do you set
and what's your your most people would
say the uh the get well plan, right? How
do you get to launch and then how do you
do your fast follow?
You know that's an important point
though is I think when often times we
are
working on developing and deploying a
system which is you know that that
happens every day all day long in in
most organizations if they've got
technology there. Um but the the
challenge is the the things that you're
not anticipating that do come up no
matter what it is that you're
developing. If it's a system, an
application, a platform, there are
always these things that you come across
that you didn't anticipate. And the
governance in the from the context of
seeing all the angles.
>> To me, that's one of the most valuable
things you can have because it's much
harder to miss potential gaps if you
have as many perspectives as you can
have looking at it from the different
angles. Um, you mentioned blind spots.
The hard part of them is we don't even
know we have them. And so we need to
have people that are seeing all these
different perspectives.
>> Some of those blind spots are are in all
truth. Sometimes they're benign.
Oftentimes they are actually very
detrimental, especially if we start
getting into some of the the the more uh
le like you know the the legal aspects
of things and find penalties.
That's and that that's only just
scratching the surface. That's not even
exploring branding impacts. That's not
exploring your lifetime value impacts.
Um, anything that basically could have
negative effects on your business.
These things that as hard as they are to
kind of implement and get moving on,
they do finally get to get you to a much
better place in terms of what I what I
think is important is trust. So
in your experience and going through
different implementations and figuring
some of the things out that you've been
talking talking about already, you know,
what does that trust start to look like
inside of an organization as you as
you're maturing and going through these
processes?
>> It's uh honestly it's not easy. So it it
looks like a number of different things.
Uh it it's most I think most people who
probably will be listening in are going
to be no stranger to walking the tight
rope. You obviously have some uh we'll
say there's some sort of objective
that's been set. You know, probably at
the most senior of levels in you know
executive leadership and you're you're
now trying to also balance out against
what you know could have some very
adverse effects while also balancing
against that. You know, one of the
things that I look at is are there
alternative ways to still get to, you
know, say you had a um we'll say you had
a savings goal for the year, right? Are
are you do you have alternative ways to
obtain that savings that perhaps was not
what you originally thought? You know,
maybe it your original thought was let's
automate something in the foreground.
you know, let's say maybe we do a
generative readout to your customers,
but then that has a lot of risks
attached to it. Is there a way to be
able to build trust in your experience
first while also building the muscle for
generative experiences maybe in the
future? And how do you also gain some
efficiencies leveraging those generative
experiences to streamline or reduce
effort when you get into and we'll we'll
use a contact center connection. when
you finally get to say that upfront IVR
800 number and you get it to the to the
agent or the associate or the person at
the front desk, whomever is taking that
call, what are ways that we're
offloading the effort on their part um
so that the costs that are associated
with that start to become less. I think
the interesting piece of it is there's
there's a lot of different angles that
we look at this, you know, the trust
piece of it, but there's the trust in
people, which we we touched on a little
bit, but now when you're talking about
the recommendations,
how do you see uh really overcoming some
of the barriers to to helping clinicians
to get comfortable to trust
recommendations or or to at least, you
know, be able to assess whether they're
they're you know, really solid or not.
And then similarly, if you talk a little
bit about the what what's like on the
other side of it, because it's really
the patient and the provider
relationships or the patient and the
nurse relationships,
those are really what we're trying to
make sure that we protect and preserve.
But it seems like if we're not doing
things purposefully, we could really
mess up in the trust arena that could
cause those things to go completely
opposite for where from where we want to
go.
>> That's precisely right. And and part of
that trust building is also knowing when
it's personal,
which the more personal something gets,
the less likely you're going to get
trust out of a person to want to go to a
machine. Whereas if it's something that
is like, you know, say I went on Amazon
to go buy a pair of sneakers that yeah,
that there's some personal aspect to
that because maybe I just need the new
pair of shoes, but if I don't get that
new pair of shoes, you know, I'll still
be alive.
When we're talking about health care,
which is extremely personal, and we we
talk about, you know, we we'll even look
at it through the lens of provider and
patient and and not only provider to
patient, but also we'll add in the
insurance company, the payer, right?
It's very personal at that point,
especially for the patient in the
middle, right? Patients don't go to the
to the hospital just for fun, god
forbid. And I I never I never want to
like you know stomp on anybody who
actually suffers from from conditions
like this unless you have a you know a
medical condition where it's like uh but
um patients are going for to providers
because there's something that they need
to have addressed. There's something
with their health that's at at stake and
>> it's survival. It's not um it this isn't
something that you know you want to put
in front of a machine. So trust building
in in a personal experience you really
need a human in the middle in order to
be able to build that trust. A machine
is never going to be able to quote
unquote understand
what it is I might be going through. It
can mimic language to suggest that.
a human on the other side is going to
snap and react very quickly.
>> Yeah. And that's a yeah and that's a
huge uh a huge point of emphasis that I
think we should really make sure that we
we touch on more probably even more so
uh in the coming uh months ahead because
the human relationship piece of it is
absolutely essential and when you have
when you think about where somebody's
state of mind might be when they're
going to the doctor there's already a
deficit that that we need to address and
what that there's something that's not
going just swimmingly for them,
>> right?
>> And so it's really really important that
we we make sure that we're not trying to
get the technology to somehow act
empathetically. That's not that's really
not going to be helpful because it
cannot it can't read body language.
Well, I mean there there could be some
technology on this, you know,
theoretically, but I don't even think we
care about that. We don't want that.
people don't you know when something
breaks I don't know about you but I
don't want the automated line when I
call
>> right right I I want to talk to a person
it's funny because you mentioned body
language there's there's also a hidden
language because most of the
applications right now you know to your
point it's not able to read body
language it's and large a lot of that is
because of the limitations of what
medium is being used I'm picking up a
phone. Well, it's that's purely audio.
I'm typing in a chat window. Well,
that's just words on a screen, but
there's a hidden language when we're in
in an audio um conversation, for
example, awkward silences.
Maybe it's a you can hear a tonal change
in the person, frustration. Um,
>> sure.
>> Or distress. and and these are are
things that the machine is not able to
respond and react to effectively. Um
plenty of people that are trying to to
make that a reality, but when you have a
a you know a very personal situation
going on, you don't want to guess that
they're having a bad situation. You want
to be absolutely pinpoint right that
they're having a bad situation,
>> right? Yeah. I think you're you're
hitting on something that I think is is
another place where we need to build
some things into our our workflows that
purposefully give us a moment to pause
and and really consider where are things
exactly at this moment and are there are
there things that I should be thinking
about differently based on what I just
heard or what I just saw. AI is
basically for for lack of a better ter
phrase it's it's almost a a decision
tree type of thing that you're dealing
with and it's looking for one or three
answers and you give it a fourth one.
>> What's it going to do with that? Right?
We have to have some mechanisms at least
from a a procedural standpoint that
we're when we're working in in deploying
the technology that there are pauses at
strategic moments where you're enabling
the human judgment to step in and do
what it needs to do.
>> Exactly. And and now it it's with now we
have um generative capabilities. I
really do call it like mimicking a
person at this stage where you know you
have your branches um you you supply
this fourth option. It's an
unpredictable item right people in in
their very nature in the in the core of
how we engage in dialogue. You can
predict to a certain extent but there's
always room for unpredictability. So now
we are also in the realm of you know
maybe you have the guardrail to stop a
random inject and contain it. Without
that guardrail though you could run into
a situation where depending on how
creative you set it up the bot will
start to and I hate this term with all
my soul hallucinate. I more personally
say it's just making stuff up. If you
were to treat it like a person, what
would you say? Well, the person's
thinking on the fly and they're making
up whatever like they're thinking in
real time and they're making up an
answer based off of what knowledge they
have and what intelligence they have
exposure to.
>> Yeah, this this is a this is a crazy
time that we're living in. I mean, I
remember back in the was it the two
early 2000s, you know, when the internet
was was still relatively new. I mean,
like you could hear me
get firing up the modem on my my tiny
little Macintosh computer that my phone
can outperform now by what I don't know,
a million%.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Back in the uh Well, so let's see. Uh so
when modems were like first coming out
like 144k, I think. And then you know
>> 9 I had a 9600 at one point.
>> Oh boy. Oh man. So like that's that's uh
even slower still.
>> Yep.
Yeah. It's crazy. I don't know if I
wouldn't have believed that we, you
know, we would deal with the technology
that we are back then. I I was I thought
what we were doing then was pretty
pretty amazing.
>> Yeah.
>> The fact that I could actually I could
actually write basic and make that make
a create a formula that would just count
infinitely.
I thought that was great. I created the
nice little loop. Yeah. not not so
earthshattering anymore. So, I want to
kind of pivot a little bit because we're
we're kind of getting getting to the
end. I I want I don't want to miss the
an opportunity just to talk a little bit
about where you see some uh
opportunities where leadership needs to
start to think and and do things a
little bit differently because I think
they we're talking about governance
again. We're not talking about, you
know, controlling and stopping things.
We're talking about enabling them. But
there needs to be some structure and
some framework and guidelines that
really help to keep us focused in the
right areas, make sure that we're moving
in the right directions. We understand
the organizational tolerance for risk.
Uh we also understand, you know, what
the legal ramifications are
>> um for the whatif scenarios that maybe
we're thinking about, maybe we're not.
Um but what would what are you thinking
about and what are you telling folks um
as you're talking to organizational
leadership um potentially board members?
How should they be thinking about it?
And you know what do we need to be
considering differently than we do today
in terms of how we over overseeing
things?
>> Yeah. Yeah. My my so first and foremost
uh wi with all of this right a lot of
what my messaging tends to be is
centered on getting a your framework in
order treat what you have as an employee
as as maybe as untasteful maybe because
I know that there's some folks uh like
McKenzie has some some order of of like
some thousand employees that are all
badged as AI employees, but there's some
soundness behind that, right? If you
treat what you have as an employee, so
remove AI from your vernacular and and
think of it as it's a junior grade
employee. What would you be doing to
support that employee? Right? you would
have onboarding um instructions for
making sure that that employee can
become effective within their first, you
know, 30, 60, 90 days.
with an AI tool that you're introducing,
if you treat it like an employee, you
might have a longer runway, but you'll
more than likely develop something that
will actually benefit you for far longer
than your average average employee you
hire.
>> And then we have to also look at it as
it it's never going to mature past the
junior employee stage. So what does the
support staff look like around
supporting that employee? What kind of
remedial training do we have to
administer on a routine basis? when new
policy is being determined and it is
being implemented just like as you would
with a a um another employee within your
organization
uh you need to consider the training
timeline
>> for getting that person up to speed. So
that that that's definitely the the
epicenter of messaging that that I have.
And then um there was a second point and
uh and unfortunately my thought train
took off and uh we got very wrapped up
in that one. I'm sure it'll come back to
me at a later day.
>> Well, I I think the the really important
distinction that and I love the way you
frame it. Think of it as an employee
because it makes a lot of sense to do
that. And why it's so different is we're
used to putting technology in place
that's really automating rulebased
tasks. And it's you can turn it on, you
have to, you know, feed it some
electricity. You might have to, you
know, tune things up once in a while.
What when we're talking about equipment,
computers or whatever. This is different
in that what we're implementing will
continue to evolve. It'll continue to
learn. It actually is interesting
because if we don't miss the
opportunity, we might be able to make
some significant improvements in how we
even understand medicine because
medicine medicine is an evolving
science. Always has been. But yet when
we try to measure things from a quality
standpoint, we're treating it like it's
static and it never has been.
>> Right? So you know this governance in a
process and in how we think about it
really needs to be constru constructed
differently so that has that
understanding and then it has to
continue to be adapted because when we
approve something today 6 months from
now the approval is based on something
that's no longer true usually because
this this capability is going to
continue to advance. Right. So I I love
the way you put that
>> with everything that you were saying
there too Chris you you actually uh jog
my memory uh that the train came back
into the station. The second point is if
you are treating it like an employee
assume that it will make mistakes not
that it might make a mistake. And as you
think about that,
design your support struts, your
framework for when those mistakes
happen. What is your your policy and and
process and procedure for those
mistakes? In a world like healthcare, uh
the the most common mistake that I see
come up is usually
it's not intentional in any way or
malicious. uh but it would be an
unintentional breach of PHI
and now I've accidentally disclosed
information I should not have and anyone
who all of us in the in the healthcare
industry as we all know you have a
policy in place in your organization for
a a a breach happened now we go and
disclose it we self-report and that
protects ourselves and And it also
strengthens ourselves so that we protect
our our patients and our members in the
future that we we don't have one leak
become a million leaks.
>> That's there's just a little bit of a
difference between there between those
points. I think that's a very well put
framing for that. Um, so as we're kind
of wrapping up here, uh, we've talked
about, you know, moving fast and, you
know, the the areas where we need to
make sure that we're taking the right
steps. Not we don't want to slow
progress. We do want to make sure that
we're doing things at a at a logical and
a responsible pace. And we make we we do
have to make sure we've got people
looking out for the blind spots that we
have. It's always going to have to be
there, unfortunately. But that's that's
life. We're human beings. And you know,
I don't know about you, but I have
friends and family members who have
probably saved my neck more times than I
could count because they saw something I
didn't see.
>> I mean, I would be lying if uh if I were
to say like, "Oh, yeah. I've never had a
a thing come up." Um we we've all been
there, right? Um and and call it our
guardian angel or whatever you want to
call it, but yeah, we're just it's part
of human nature.
Well, if I could have you just think
about the this for, you know, as we wrap
up, if you think about looking ahead in
your crystal ball, what what do you
think the next 5 years is going to be
the thing that's going to make the
difference between organizations that
really implement uh effectively and
manage well uh using these a AI
technologies versus ones who may fall
down and not have the success that
they're they're aiming to have? Yeah, I
I I in my heart of hearts, um I I think
that the the the biggest uh
differentiator is going to come down to
the organizations that can effectively
structure themselves to treat this AI as
an employee.
Regardless of where you put it in your
configuration, regardless of how you
think it might be protected, treat it as
though it's a person. Don't call it a
person, of course, right? It's still not
a human at the end of the day. But if
you were to to center your thought on
that, those organizations that can build
frameworks
and governance around that, those
organizations will have staying power
from now until the next big disruptor
comes out. Um, and then we get to do the
merrygoround all over again.
>> I I like what how you you frame that and
I think it's an important thing to note
as well. um we are dealing with a period
of time where people are pretty uh
uncomfortable and they're they're
nervous about their jobs being replaced
and all that. And so when when we're
talking about you know treating it as an
employee the the intent here is is
really around making sure that we
understand that it's going to continue
to evolve and grow. It has nothing to do
with with what what the f the role or
even the function is. It's that it needs
supervision. And it's artificial.
Artificial means not real. And well, in
my simplest understanding of the term,
maybe it's not exactly correct, but we
do need to treat it that way. Um, but
not not framing it as it's it's just a
human being. Well, this is evidence.
You're going to try to replace me with a
machine,
>> right? That's not what we're talking
about.
>> It it it's uh I mean, to put it bluntly,
it it knows how to mimic to a certain
extent. kind of think of it like a
parrot, right? Parrots are incredible
creatures that can mimic human speech,
human sounds,
but it itself is not a human being. It's
not effective at interpreting
um all of our language there. They do.
Of course, you know, an animal is going
to be a little bit closer to having
emotions and feelings, but it it's it's
pariting back information that it has
been fed. So, it it is the ultimate
imitator human um human language and
human engagement that we have seen in
the entire history of the human race.
>> And absolutely, it's this has been a
fascinating conversation. Uh Brian, I
really really appreciate you you taking
the time. I was looking forward to it.
You uh certainly haven't disappointed
and I really appreciate the the great
conversation. Um, you know, as we
continue to fight the fight and carry
on, it's nice to know that, you know, I
have a another friend out there who's
who's really trying to pay attention to
the things that really matter. making
sure that we're doing the things that
are making this an enhancement and an
enabler for for humanity as opposed to a
replacement for anything else except for
maybe uh very inefficient workflows that
we've tended to gloss over or haven't
noticed because we didn't keep all the
right humans in the loop when we were
designing things. That's it for this
episode of the Signal Room. If today's
conversation sparked something in you,
an idea, a challenge, or a perspective
worth amplifying, I'd love to hear from
you. Message me on LinkedIn or visit
sigaroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.